EGOR PHILIPPOV

Senior Software Engineer

egor@philippov.ca • github.com/lone-cloud linkedin.com/in/egor-philippov • egor.philippov.ca

ABOUT

A passionate technology professional with the ability to work on all parts of an application, be it on the server, browser or mobile.

Highly adaptable, innovative and articulate communicator specializing in building world class web applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PANASONIC REMOTE

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

APR 2020 - SEPT 2024

- Systems design and full stack development of <u>yohana.com</u> and <u>app.yohana.com</u>.
- Full stack development using Next.js (TypeScript + React + Node.js) and backend development of gRPC microservices using Micronaut (Kotlin). Implementation was based on collaboration with product and design teams in Figma and Slack.
- Established and enforced best software development practices (strong typing, linting, spell checking, etc..), enforcing accessibility guidelines, running interviews, CI/CD implementation and general build + deployment automation.
- Wrote and automated the automatic re-publishing of a library for sharing the protobuf types between Kotlin and TypeScript projects.
- Implemented rich, HTML-based, litmus-tested email templates and a related client library.
- Full stack development and prompt-engineering of AI-based assistants using OpenAI's GPT-40 with custom functions for real-time data fetching.

GOOGLE REMOTE & PALO ALTO, US **FULL STACK ENGINEER OCT 2016 - Apr 2020**

- Full stack development of various various enterprise applications for Google Store and Nest including enterprise.nest.com, hvac.nest.com and home.nest.com/login.
- Full stack development using Ember.js and Golang.

ABSOLUTE SOFTWARE VANCOUVER, CANADA SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER JAN 2014-Oct 2016

Full stack development using Java EE and Ember.js of enterprise web applications for remote management of

company owned mobile devices.

OPENBET TECHNOLOGIES

BURNABY, CANADA

JUNIOR - INTERMEDIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

AUG 2012 - Jan 2014

• Full stack development using TCL and Backbone.js of an online casino and sports betting portal for a Canadian casino at playnow.com.

SAP VANCOUVER, CANADA

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SEPT 2009 - Sept 2010

• Java development of installation software for a business intelligence suite (Crystal Reports).

EDUCATION

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

BURNABY, Canada

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTING SCIENCE

2008 - 2012